你和辛西娅一起会成为无人能敌的二人组
Together, you and Cynthia could be an unstoppable duo.
想成为新的穿越者吗
You wanna be the new Breacher?
你的思考帽和暗物质正是造成这个的罪魁祸首
Your Thinking Cap and the dark matter is what caused this.
我知道
I know!
还有多久我会忘记一切
How long before everything I know is gone?
迪沃干掉了所有会碍事的人
DeVoe has taken out everyone who's gotten in his way.
他创造了12个超能力者好让他窃取其超能力
He created 12 meta-humans, just so he could steal their powers.
他为什么需要他们的力量
Why does he need their powers?
烧毁闪电侠小队的大火
The fire that burns down Team Flash
将会照亮通往大悟之道的道路
will also light the path to the Enlightenment.
牛津大学
自启蒙时代
Since the age of Enlightenment,
那个理性  论辩及对真理的探索繁盛的时代以来
when reason, debate, and the search for truth flourished,
八年前
人类用尽一切手段不断地推动世界进步
the world has improved by nearly every measure
并将继续如此
in human advancement, and continues to do so.
我毫不怀疑
There is no doubt in my mind
随着科技不断昌盛
that as technology continues to bloom,
人类也将继续繁荣
so will all of humanity.
迪沃教授
Professor DeVoe?
你有异议
You disagree?
对
Well, uh, yes, I guess.
我对与科技与人性
Just, I have a more realistic view
有更现实的看法
of humanity whenever technology is concerned.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你谈到启蒙运动
Well, you spoke of the Enlightenment.
我们得以史为鉴
One only has to look at history to find the answers.
行
Okay, let's.
过去两个世纪内平均寿命
Life expectancy over the past two centuries
从30年增长到接近70年
has increased from 30 years to nearly 70 years.
而这是件好事吗
And-and we should assume that's a good thing?
每过一天  我们都得和
Each new day, we have to share
多达二十万的新生儿分享非常有限的资源
very limited resources with anything up to 200,000 newborn babies,
他们大多最后都会生活在
most of whom will end up living
赤贫与饥寒中
in abject poverty and famine.
非常感谢  前景黯淡教授
Well, thank you very much, Professor Doom and Gloom.
提醒我千万别去听你的历史课
Remind me never to take one of your history classes.
也许你应该听听  我有很多能教给你的东西
Perhaps you should. There's much I could teach you.
道教徒为了追求永生
The Taoists, in pursuit of immortality,
发明了黑火药
discovered gunpowder.
阿尔弗雷德·诺贝尔设立了诺贝尔奖
Alfred Nobel created the Nobel Prize so he wouldn't be remembered
大家就不记得他发明了炸药
as the man who invented dynamite.
历史一次又一次告诉我们
History has shown us time and time again
每当一项新科技
that whenever a technological advancement
可以用来伤害人类时  它总会被这么用
can be used to hurt humanity, it will be.
你不能因人类使用科技的方式
You can't blame technology for the way
而责怪科技  教授
men choose to use it, Professor.
你不能否认最杰出的人类的
You can't ignore that the best of ideas
最天才的创想总是用于歧途
by the smartest of men often have a way of becoming corrupted.
范德米尔钢铁
你已经定位了我们需要的所有东西
You've located everything we need.
现在到取回它们的时候了
And now the time has come to retrieve it
我们终于可以
so we can finally...
开启大悟之道了
enlighten the world.
闪 电 侠
第四季
第二十集
宝贝
Hey, babe.
是我  就是说一下
Uh, it's me. Just checking in.
替我爸
For my dad.
他特别想知道你对
He... really wants to know your answer
接不接手穿越者职务
about taking the Breacher job.
他原话是
I think his exact words were:
那个缺犊子最好告诉我
"That little son of a Breach better tell me,
要不他们永远也找不到尸体
or they will never find the body."
但是他退休了  他可以等
Yeah. But you know what? He's retired. He can wait.
所以你爱花多久花多久
So just take as much time as you need.
-好吗  -别说这没什么
- Okay? It's, um-- - Don't say it's fine.
-你知道  -别说这没什么
- You know. - Don't say it's fine.
-这没什么  -天哪
- It's fine. - Oh, God.
-这没什么  -好吧
- It's fine. - Okay.
随时联系我
So, just five me. Whenever.
再见
Okay. Bye.
拉蒙  极速实验室  现在
Ramon, speed lab. Now.
好
Good! Good, good, good.
Good, good, good good, good.
要让冰霜杀手出现
Thing we're gonna do to get Killer Frost
让你的肾上腺素激增
to appear, get that massive spike
到我们需要的程度  我们要做的是
in your adrenaline production that we need,
让拉蒙用他的震波
is, Ramon is gonna use his vibes
震动你的每个细胞
to shake you up on the cellular level,
然后看看我们能不能让你的老朋友
and let's see if we can't get your old friend
冰霜杀手出来玩
Killer Frost to come out to play.
你确定这有用吗
Are you sure this is gonna work?
像其他假说一样
Well, I mean, like any hypothesis,
实践出真知嘛
you have to test it to get an answer.
这是我们从四年级以后一直做的事情  又叫
It's what we've all done since the fourth grade, known as the...
科学方法
Scientific method?
没错  艾伦
Right you are, Allen!
当然  他到了
Of course. Ah, here he is.
好  就位
Okay, good. So get in position.
别担心  我降低了这东西上的电流
Don't worry, I lowered the amps on this thing.
拉蒙  你就位了吗
Ramon, you set?
对
Yeah.
斯诺  你准备好了吗
Snow, you ready?
好了
I'm ready.
三  二  一
Three, two, one, and...
什么也没有
Nothing.
拉蒙  用更大的力量
All right. Ramon, more power.
好了吗  三  二  一
Set? Three, two, one--
这没用
All right, this isn't working.
拉蒙  用全力
You know what, Ramon? Full power.
等等  你什么意思
Wait, hold on, hold on. What do you mean,
用全力  我们不想把凯特琳震到
full power? We don't want to blast Caitlin
极速实验室那一头
across the speed lab.
你得刺激她的肾上腺素
Well, you need to get a spike in her adrenaline.
-哈里  她可能会受伤  -对
- Harry, she could get injured. - Yeah.
天哪  这
God, this is--
这会管用的  好吗  没有东西被改变对吧
look, this is gonna work, okay? Nothing has changed. All right?
斯诺的DNA测试证实了这点
Snow's DNA tests, they confirm it.
她的超能力DNA没有被诺亚的能力毁掉
Her meta-DNA was not spliced by Noah's powers.
你是说融点的超能力
You mean Melting Point's powers.
对  我说的就是这个  融点的超能力
Right, that's what I said. Melting Point's powers.
-你不是这么说的  -我是这么说的
- No, you didn't. - I did say that.
但是  哈里
But, Harry,
她的系统中根本没有暗物质啊
there's no dark matter in her system anyway.
我们只是在这里刺激她的心率
We're just trying to spike her heart rate.
你什么意思  没有暗物质
What do you mean, there's no dark matter?
哈里  你知道这个的
Harry, you knew that.
我们都知道
We all did.
我们知道吗  我们知道  不  我知道
We did? We did. No, I know.
我就是  忘了
I just, I think I just, you know, forget.
我忘了
I forgot.
你忘了
You forgot?
哈里  你还好吗
Harry, are you okay?
不  他不好
No. He's not.
哈里  你在
Harry, you're...
丧失智力  没错
Losing my intelligence? Yes.
思考帽注入的暗物质
The injection of dark matter from the Thinking Cap
显然使我的神经突触过载了
apparently overwhelmed my synapses.
它不但没有加速我的大脑
Instead of making my brain faster,
反而让它迟钝了
it's... slowing it down.
你为什么不早点告诉我们
Why didn't you tell us this sooner?
还有多久
How long until...
没办法知道
No way of knowing.
有时候我能清晰地思考
I mean, there are days I can think clearly
有时候
and other days...
我不能
I... I can't.
好消息是  从我知道的来讲
The good news is, um, from what I can see,
这种衰退是可逆的
the regression seems to be reversible.
太好了
Okay, great.
我马上全力研究这个
I'll start working on it full-time.
不  你不能
No, you won't.
我自作自受
I did this to myself,
我以为
and I-I thought "Oh, you know what?
使用思考帽
"Use that Thinking Cap,
我就比迪沃聪明然后可以阻止迪沃
and then I can outthink Devoe and then stop DeVoe."
我错了  结果我们就变成这样
I was wrong. Now here we are.
我们会解决这事的
Okay, well, we're gonna fix this.
你我都知道时间有限
You and I both know there's a ticking clock...
我现在这样不能帮助任何人
and I can't help anyone like this.
不  你能
Yes, you can.
怎么帮
How?
伙计们
Look, guys.
拉尔夫
Ralph...
凯特琳失去力量  现在又是这件事
Caitlyn's powers, now this.
迪沃对如何拆散我们知之甚详
DeVoe knew how to break us apart, but...
但我们还在一起
I mean, we're all still here.
我们是一家人
We're a family.
这就是我们打败迪沃的办法
That's how we're gonna beat DeVoe.
好吧  艾伦
All right, Allen.
好吧
All right.
范德米尔钢铁
Vandermeer Steel.
比我想的要小
Smaller than I expected.
大悟之道的第一步
The first step to our Enlightenment is as simple...
易如反掌
as opening a door.
1771合金
Alloy 1771.
这里面的镓锑基
Now, the gallium antimonide substrates within these
能效利用达到400%
can harness power at 400% efficiency.
我精确计算过
The precise amount, I calculated.
你可以拿起来了
You can pick 'em up.
不许动
Freeze!
你应该让我们走
You should let us leave.
不可以
I can't do that.
可以
Yes, you can.
怎么回事
How are you...
我们拿到我们需要的了
We have what we need.
我同意
I suppose we do.
紧急情况
Code Red! Code Red!
克利福德  没有必要
Clifford. This is unnecessary.
你知道我们开始后会有连带伤亡
You knew there were gonna be casualties when we began.
这是他自找的
This is his own doing.
是的  我的爱人
Yes, my love.
什么情况
What are we dealing with?
首先  我们试图确定
First of all, we're trying to determine
保险库里是什么
what was in that vault.
小心脚下
Watch your step right here.
没有钻孔  没有撬锁
There was no drilling, there was no lock picked.
即使有人告诉我们
And the only thing anybody would tell us
保险库里是什么
about what was in the vault was that
也是某种神秘科技
it was some sort of secretive technology.
还有这里的保安
Also, security guard here
24岁  显然枪杀了自己
was a 24-year-old, apparently shot himself.
等等  盗窃和自杀
Wait, a robbery and a suicide?
他才结婚
He was newly married.
家里有小婴儿
Has an infant at home.
我感觉是超能力搞出来的事
This is smelling like some meta madness to me.
还有谁可以"基尔戈"过视网膜扫瞄  "德比"过保险柜锁
Who else can "Kilgore" a retinal scan and "Dibny" A vault lock?
好吧  我去问些人看看能否
Okay, well, I'm gonna go interview some people,
找出些什么
see what I can find out.
好吧  西斯科和我试着找出迪沃偷了什么
All right, Cisco and I will try to figure out what DeVoe stole.
好的  我去那里
All right. I'll be over here.
我们从哪开始呢
Okay, so. Where should we start?
我想  如果我们可以取得
I'm thinking: if we can gain acc--
文件权限
...to their files...
1771合金
Alloy 1771?
这是库存文件里唯一丢失的东西
It's the only item missing from the inventory files.
或者我就站在这里养眼
Or I can just... stand here and look pretty.
你知道你可以做什么吗
Hey, know what you can do, actually?
你可以震波那把枪
You could vibe the gun.
文件没有说1771合金是什么
The file didn't say what Alloy 1771 was.
所以我们需要另一种方式了解
So we need another way to learn
为什么迪沃想要它
why DeVoe would want it.
迪沃震不得  还记得吗
Uh, vibing and DeVoe do not mix, remember?
我知道  但我的意思是
Yeah, I know, man. But I mean,
我们能做什么呢  这是唯一的办法
what are we supposed to do? It's the only way.
巴里  我真的不想现在
Barry, I don't really feel like
被炸到撞墙
getting blasted into a wall right now.
我相信我们能用另一种办法
I'm sure there's another way we can
找出这是什么
find out what this is that doesn't
而不需要我脑震荡
require me getting a migraine.
是个太阳能板
It is a solar panel.
由能够以400%的能效
Constructed of metal that absorbs
吸收放大太阳能的金属制造
and multiplies the sun's energy at 400% efficiency.
迪沃想拿太阳能板做什么
What would DeVoe be doing with a solar panel?
只靠它的话  没什么
Nothing, on its own.
他一定是要建什么东西
He's gotta be building something.
我需要你震波这把枪
Look, I-I need you to vibe the gun.
也许我应该用电影给你解释
Maybe I should put this in movie terms for you.
有关迪沃的所有就像是《小鬼当家》里的房子
Everything in DeVoe's wake is like the "Home Alone" House.
好吗  是陷阱
Okay? It's booby-trapped.
我需要两倍能力
I would need to double my powers
试图震波那把枪
just to even attempt to vibe the gun.
等等  吉普赛
Well, hold on. I mean, could--
可以加倍你的能力吗
could Gypsy double your powers?
-好主意  -不
- That's a good idea. - No, not.
不什么
Not what?
吉普赛很忙
Gypsy's busy.
她爸爸刚退休
Her dad just retired.
她需要做双份工作
She's having to do double the work.
地球19现在很乱  她没空
Earth 19 is a mess right now. She's swamped.
西斯科
Cisco.
联合你们两个的能力可以的
Combining your powers could make it
我们就知道迪沃要做什么了
so we know DeVoe's next move.
谢谢你来见我
Thanks for meeting me.
-我需要你帮忙  -好的
- I need a favor. - Okay.
我需要你转移一下塞西尔的注意力
I need you to distract Cecile for a while.
为什么
What for?
是这样的
Well, that's the thing.
我不能告诉你  因为如果我告诉你
I can't tell you, because if I do,
她读你的思想就知道了
she'll read your mind and find out.
为什么不找爱瑞丝
Why can't Iris do it?
因为爱瑞丝恰好知道
Because Iris knows exactly why
为什么我要塞西尔分心
I'm trying to distract Cecile.
所以巴里知道
And therefore Barry knows.
意味着西斯科知道  孩子们知道
Which means that Cisco knows, Kid knows.
-没问题  -真的吗
- Whatever you need. - Really?
-是的  -谢谢
- Yeah. - Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome. All right.
丢了脑子  成了保姆
Lose my mind, become a babysitter.
别这样
Oh, come on.
如果有人会逆转发生的事情
Listen, if anybody's gonna reverse what's happening,
绝对会是尖端科研实验室的孩子们
it's gonna be those kids at S.T.A.R. Labs.
他们爱你  哈里
I mean, they love you, Harry.
他们绝不会放弃帮助你
And they will never stop trying to help you.
-别丧气  -好吧
- So don't lose hope. - Right.
这就是我怎么拿下传热学导论的
And that is how I aced my intro to heat transfer
在我大学的第一年
my first year at university.
厉害
Bravo.
应付自如
Ducked and run.
我怀念那个时候
I miss those days.
当时我年轻愚蠢又勇敢
I was young and foolish and brave.
现在你只有愚蠢了
And now you're just foolish.
同意和第一次见面就
To agree to a date with someone
无礼地质疑
I first met as they were so rudely
我专业看法的人约会
disagreeing with my professional opinion.
愚蠢  也许吧
Foolish, maybe.
还没有人这么挑战过我
Yeah, no one's ever challenged me like that.
很新奇
It was refreshing.
也许你说得对  科技会使我们分心
Ah, maybe you are right about technology's distracting us.
确实会毁了好时光
It certainly can destroy moments.
尽管如此  有时
Although, sometimes...
科技
technology...
也会创造好时光
can create them as well.
谢谢你过来帮我们  吉普赛
Thanks for coming to help us, Gypsy.
轮到你们两个了
You two are up.
我们该怎么做呢
So, how do we do this?
为了合震波  我们必须完全同步
Okay, so to co-vibe, we have to be totally in sync.
我们想的必须完全一样
All right? Our minds have to be on exactly the same page.
和往常一样
Just like always.
是的
Yeah.
这就奇怪了
Oh. So that was weird.
怎么了  你们看到了什么
Why? What did you see?
不知道  一个码头
I don't know, a-a dock?
看起来像个集装箱
Um, looked like a shipping container.
16号
Number 16.
一定是迪沃接下来要偷的
That must be what DeVoe is gonna steal next.
他得从我们这里偷了
He's gonna have to steal it from us.
好的
All right.
看起来我们及时赶来了
It looks like we made it in time.
不管集装箱里是什么  我们不能让迪沃拿到
Whatever's in this container, we can't let DeVoe have it.
实际上
Actually...
是这个集装箱里的东西
it's what's in... this container
你不能让我拿到
you can't let me have.
这个集装箱原有的
what was in this container.
打他
Hit him!
感谢你们
Gratitude...
让我锻炼一下  一如既往
for the workout, brief as it was.
再见
Later.
该死
Damn it. Damn it!
为什么我们没有看到正确的集装箱编号
Why didn't we see the right container number?
有人的震波不够清楚  西斯科
Someone's vibe wasn't clear enough, Cisco.
你在怪我吗
Are you blaming me?
你分心了  我能说什么
You lost your focus, what can I say?
撞了金属集装箱
Yeah, getting hit against a metal container wall
会这样
sort of does that.
我也撞了的
You know, I hit that wall too.
我很专心
I'm perfectly focused.
如果你那么专心
Oh, well, if you're so focused,
为什么你还让他跑了
then why'd you let him get away?
别试图怪在我头上
Don't even try and put that on me.
抱歉  我没有怪在你头上
I'm sorry, I didn't put that on you.
是你责怪自己
You put that on you.
我要一拳打你脸上
I'm gonna put my fist in your face,
我要做的
is what I'm gonna--
如果我接受了那份工作
Is that how we'd work together
这就是我们如何合作的吗
if I took the job?
各位  什么工作
Guys. What job?
我拿来了运输集装箱的金属块
I brought that metal piece from the shipping container,
以防我们一会儿要合震波  但是
in case we want to try co-vibing later, but...
我想我们都看见了会怎么样
think we both saw where that led us, so...
你之前说过  穿越者退休了
So you said... Breacher retired.
他让你去地球19替代他  对吧
He offered you a job on Earth 19 to replace him, didn't he?
我就随便猜一下
You know, another shot in the dark,
你还没有给穿越者
but you haven't actually given Breacher
或是吉普赛一个回答
or Gypsy an answer yet.
你比较倾向哪边
Which way you leaning?
我非常想和吉普赛在一起
I wanna be with Gypsy more than anything.
只是这很复杂
It's just complicated.
不是的  我理解
Hey, no, man, I get it.
不过  我是说...
But look, I mean...
也许
maybe...
你们一起来结束这一切
you guys working together to end this
会让决定更容易一些  你俩都是
will make the decision easier, for both of you.
万一她想要的和我不一样呢
What if she doesn't want the same thing as me?
你要是不问永远不会知道
I mean, you're never gonna know unless you ask.
还有  西斯科  我觉得...
And listen, Cisco, I mean...
我们没有你无法打败迪沃
we can't beat DeVoe without you.
你是我们的秘密武器
You're our secret weapon.
你和吉普赛得意见统一
You and Gypsy just need to be
才能让武器起作用
on the same page for that weapon to work.
是  但我不知道我们做不做得到
Yeah, and I don't know that we can be.
好吧  那就...
All right, well...
让我帮助你
let me help you.
-巴里  -你等一下
- Barry. - No, I... hold on.
这结果可一定会好
So that's gonna end well.
最后一个
Last one.
好了  我们  需要食物
Okay, we, uh, need food.
我们需要酒
We need wine.
两个都需要很多  去吧
Lots of both. Go.
我去开包裹
I'll unpack.
克利福德
Clifford!
去吧  早点回来
Go. Hurry home.
我可以留下来  你确定吧
I can stay, if-you're sure?
-确定  -我真的应该留下
- Yeah. - I really should.
最后一次机会
Last chance.
展示我们的未来
我  猎人
Me, hunter!
我为我的女王猎食
Me hunted feast for my queen!
你不是真的相信你日记写的这些东西吧
You don't believe these things you wrote in this journal, do you?
读起来像是某种激进的宣言  克利福德
This reads like some radical's manifesto, Clifford.
这是现实主义者的觉醒
It is a realist's awakening.
你向所有科技慈善家发起了挑战
You declare war against every technological philanthropist.
这么一群人
Men, men, men.
用他们的"发明"
Pushing us to the brink of Armageddon
将我们推向末日
with their "Inventions."
不  他们想要人类更好
No, they want a better mankind.
别天真了  马尔利泽
Don't be naive, Marlize.
我们社会的严重衰落
The severity of our society's failings
需要极端的思想才能
require extreme ideas if ever we were to
恢复哪怕一点点的平衡
restore some semblance of balance.
"科技已经成了我们社会生物学中的
"Technology has become a cancerous cell
一块癌细胞"
In our social biology."
"清除它  需要一次大清洗"
"Exercising it... would require a total purge,
"不仅仅是物质的世界
"Not only of the material world,
还要是人类的意识"
but also human consciousness"?
这不是平衡  这是切除人们的脑前叶
This is not balance! This is lobotomizing people!
这是重启大众的大脑
It is rebooting the masses' brains,
让他们摆脱科技的拐杖
to let them forget their technological crutches!
他们是叼着奶嘴的婴儿
They are babies with pacifiers!
那谁来教导他们呢
Oh, and who will teach them?
你吗  教授
You, Professor?
这怎么可能帮助的了人类
How does any of this help humankind?
你看不懂吗  马尔利泽
Don't you see? Marlize...
科技在杀死我们
Our technology is killing us.
你和我  我们可以修复这一切
You and I, we can fix this.
一起
Together.
作为搭档
As partners.
我们可以领导他们  所有社会  人类
We can lead them, all of society, humanity,
带向启蒙的真正道路
on the true path to Enlightenment.
哈里
Hey, Harry.
塞西尔·霍尔顿地检官
DA Cecile Horton.
乔说你需要调整我的内心活动缓冲器
Joe said you needed to adjust my mental activity dampener.
是的  乔  是的
Yes. Joe... yes.
我是得做这个  这是个大事
I have to do that. It's, uh, it's not a big deal.
就是普通的调整
It's a standard procedure.
我就在这  好了
That's, yeah. Okay.
好了  我就位了
All right. I'm in.
现在正在安装  所以
Well, it's installing, so...
你只需要  坐着就好
now you just... you just sit.
然后等着
And wait.
等很长一段时间
For a long time.
好吧  你最近脑袋里是怎么了
Okay. What is happening with your thoughts right now?
我的...  好吧
With my... okay.
就是  有个关于暗物质的以外
So... there was an incident with dark matter--
是  我知道  乔跟我说了
Yeah, I know, I know, Joe told me about that.
我说的不是那个
That's not what I'm talking about.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你脑袋里在大喊大叫
Your thoughts are screaming at me.
就好像它们开始显现
It's like they start to form,
然后就像是
and then, it's like,
越多点子的出现
the more the ideas appear...
-就有越多的消失  -没错
- The more they disappear. - Exactly.
这倒是解释了我不行的日子
Well, that explains my "Can't" Days.
那是什么意思  哈里
What does that mean, Harry?
这意思是  塞西尔·霍尔顿地检官
It means, DA Cecile Horton,
我越多的想要使用我的大脑
that the more I try to use my brain...
我就会越快失去它
the sooner I'm going to lose it.
咖啡师  请再来一杯
Barista. Another one, please.
加双倍
Uh, make it a double.
谢谢
Thank you.
-给你 -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thanks.
我到处在找你
I've been looking everywhere for you.
一个女人就不能安静的自己摄入咖啡因吗
Can't a woman caffeinate in peace around here?
你看
Hey. Look. Hey!
我知道你为什么生气  但没关系
I know why you're upset, but it's all right.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
西斯科只是觉得他要是接受了工作
Look, Cisco just thinks if he takes the job,
他会让我们失望  但要我说
he'll be letting us down. But, I mean,
他只需要追随他自己的心
he just needs to follow his own heart,
做他想要做的  不需要担心我们
do what he needs to do, not worry about us.
他知道这一点的
He knows that.
这真是太好了
That's actually really great.
所以现在  你们只需要
So now... all you guys have to do
和对方谈谈就行了
is talk to each other.
好吧  这一部分不那么简单  所以...
Yeah. Well, that part's not so easy, so...
挺简单的
Yes... it is.
-你要干什么  -什么
- What are you doing? - What?
想都不要想  不行
Don't even think about. No!
好吧
Okay.
不许你在这么拉我跑了  懂吗
Don't ever "Whoosh" Me again, all right?
完全没问题  抱歉  西斯科
Totally, I'm sorry. Um, Cisco.
这是怎么了
What is going on?
就是让他们回到统一战线上  好吗
Just getting 'em back on the same page, okay?
西斯科  吉普赛生气  是因为说实话
Cisco, Gypsy is upset, because, frankly?
你花太多时间来接受
I mean, it's taking you too long to accept
穿越者的工作要求了  还有吉普赛
Breacher's job offer. Duh. And Gypsy.
西斯科  他只是担心会遗弃小队
Cisco, he's-he's just worried about abandoning his team.
我是说  他不是不想接受工作
I mean, it's not that he doesn't want the job.
对吧  好  所以...
Right? Okay, so...
你俩现在都清楚了  对吧
Now you both know, right?
然后你可以进来
And you can dive in and...
解决这问题  咱么一起来谈谈
work this out-let's talk about this.
中城警局报告多了两起闯入
CCPD is reporting two more break-ins
波音科技生产实验室
at tech manufacturers-Boeing Lab
和贾米森学院事件
and the Jamison Institute.
更多的硬件被偷了
More hardware was stolen.
-迪沃  -有人受伤了吗
- DeVoe. - Was anybody hurt?
三人死亡  都是警卫
Three fatalities, all of them security guards
在高等级警戒区域  就像是在范德米尔一样
in high-level clearance areas, just like at Vandermeer.
他在随意获取他想要的
He's taking whatever he wants,
杀掉所有挡在道上的人
killing anybody that gets in the way.
各位  真抱歉  但是我们得研究出
Guys, I-I'm sorry, but we have to figure out
他在制造什么机器  马上就要
what kind of machine he's building, right now.
我们得试试才行
Look, we have to try.
-你没事吧  -没事  没事
- You okay? - Yeah. Yeah.
-你没事吧  -我看到这事会发生了
- Oh, God, are you okay? - I saw that one coming.
-你还好吗  -我很好  谢谢
- You okay? - I'm good. Thank you.
他们没事吧
They okay?
测试显示  生理上他们没事
Tests show, physically, they're fine.
作为一对情侣  就不怎么样了
As a couple, not so much.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
我要去让那俩人回到一条线上
I need to get these two back in sync.
我是说  我得想办法领先
I mean, we gotta get ahead of this somehow.
等等  慢下来  牛仔
Whoa, whoa, whoa, slow down, cowboy.
你什么意思  为什么
What do you mean? Why?
也许你做的已经够多了  好吗
Maybe you've done enough already, okay?
西斯科和吉普赛显然在经历着
Cisco and Gypsy are clearly going through
一些事  而且  这不是我们
something, and, you know, it's not up to us
能劝说他们的
to counsel them through it.
那该由谁来  爱瑞丝
Well, then who is it up to, Iris?
-就先稍等一下  -我们不能等
- Just stop for a second... - We can't stop.
我们一等  所有人都会散
The second we do, everyone could fall apart.
这队伍被威胁所支撑着
The team's hanging on by a thread.
-但我们都在坚持  巴里  -能有多久
- But we are hanging on, Barry. - For how long?
看看都发生了什么
I mean, look at what's happening.
迪沃在杀害无辜的人
DeVoe is killing innocent people.
他偷走科技零件  天知道是为了什么
He's stealing pieces of tech, for God knows why.
只是为追上他就让我们分裂了
Just trying to keep up with him is tearing us apart.
亲爱的  你不能只靠自己
Babe... you can't put it on yourself
让大家团结起来
to hold everyone together.
西斯科是家人
Cisco is family.
当家人受伤时  我们都感觉到疼痛
And when family hurts, we all hurt.
我明白
I get that.
但是有时你不能替他们回答问题
But sometimes you can't answer their questions for them.
有时候你只需要支持他们
Sometimes, you just have to support them
让他们自己去寻找自我
while they find them on their own,
不论是在一起还是分开
whether they're together or they're apart.
什么
What?
就是这样
That's it.
这些科技零件无法被拼到一起
The pieces of tech don't fit together...
是因为它们本就不是要拼一起
because they're not supposed to.
他不是在制造一件东西  而是在制造好多个
He's not building one thing, he's building multiple.
哈里  我知道这很难
Harry, I know this is hard.
这的确很难  塞西尔·霍尔顿地检官
It is hard, DA Cecile Horton,
因为我的大脑  就是定义了我
because my brain, the one thing that has defined me
差不多一辈子的东西
for, well, pretty much my entire life,
就要
is about to...
消失了  那之后我又会是谁
...vanish, and then who will I be?
你还是之前的那个人
You'll be the exact same man you've always been.
是啊  但会很蠢
Yeah, but dumb.
同一个人  完全不如之前聪明
Same man. Way less intelligent.
哈里
Harry.
做一个聪明的人有很多方式
There are lots of ways to be intelligent.
并不是只能用你的大脑
Not just using your head.
好吧
Right.
等等
Wait.
再做一遍  哈里
Do that again. Harry!
-做什么  -再做一遍  再做一遍
- Do what? - Do it again! Do it again!
对吗
Right?
-你怎么做到的  -我看到它了
- How did you do that? - I saw it!
在你大脑里  在它消失之前
Inside your mind, before it vanished.
在  等等  所以你能
In... wait. So you can--
写出你正在想什么
Write down what you're thinking.
-在它  -消失之前
- Before it-- - Disappears.
是的
Yeah.
马尔利泽  我把样本拿来了
Marlize? I brought the sample.
好
Okay.
好的
All right.
交叉手指祈祷吧
Fingers crossed.
开始了
Here we go.
干杯
Cheers.
-成功了  -真的吗
- Yes! - Yeah?
-去告诉其他人  -这就去
- Show the others. - Got it.
喂
Hello?
马尔利泽
Marlize.
是我
It's me.
克利福德
Clifford.
我需要你回到家里来
I need you to come home.
我做不到
I can't.
我在帮助改变这里
I'm making a difference here--
让这里变得更好
I'm changing lives for the better.
这些人需要我
These people need me.
我需要你
I need you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我无法和把社会看作疾病
I can't be with someone that thinks that society is a disease,
相信我们的世界将被科技毁灭的人在一起
that believes that our world is being plagued by technology.
没有了你我什么都不是
I am nothing without you.
你是一个很聪明的人
You're a brilliant man
有很光明的未来
with a great future ahead of you.
如果你不在我身边
What kind of future do I have
我还有什么未来可言
if you are not by my side?
我只是希望你能够
I just wish that you could show
对其他人也抱有同样的同情心
the same compassion for the rest of humanity
就像你为我做的那样
as you do for me.
听我说  马尔利泽  我
Listen to me, Marlize, I...
我的思想  我无法
my thoughts, I cannot--
我只是  我不认为
I-I just-- I just don't think that--
马尔利泽
Marlize?
Marlize!
你刚刚想说什么
So... what were you gonna say?
在我们被打断之前
Before we were so alarmingly interrupted.
听着  我只是
Look, I just...
西斯科  我
Cisco, I--
我不想你接受那份工作
Don't want you to take the job.
真是让人松了口气
That is such a relief.
因为我不想改变任何事情
Because I don't want anything to change.
我们不仅没有站在同一边
Not only have we not been on the same page,
我们甚至都不在同一个星球上
we haven't even been on the same planet.
真正地不在
Literally.
我们这样来来回回
We've been doing this back-and-forth thing
已经快一年了
for almost a year,
讨论谁去谁的地球上
negotiating who gets to go to whose Earth
以及什么时候  只是为了见到对方
and when, just to see each other,
一旦我们终于见到彼此
and on the off-chance we do get to see each other,
就好像进入了倒计时
there's, like, a countdown
直到我们中有一个不得不离开
until one of us has to leave,
我受够这样了
and I'm tired of it!
我不想只能通过制造缺口才能见到我爱的人
I don't want to have to Breach to see the woman I love.
我想要每天早上
I want to wake up next to her.
都在她身边醒来
Every morning.
你想说什么
So what are you saying?
我在说我想要更多
I'm saying I want more.
我不想接受穿越者的工作
I'm saying I don't want Breacher's job,
但是我想要你
but I do want you.
我也想要你
I want you too.
我应该怎么做
What am I supposed to do?
收拾好我所有的东西
Pack up my entire life, everything?
忘掉我的工作  我的职责
Forget about my job, my responsibilities--
-不  不是  -然后搬到这里
- No, no, no-- - Move here?
不  我不是在要求你这样做
No, no, that's not what I'm asking you to do.
我永远不会要求你离开机构
I would never ask you to leave the Agency.
我知道这对你来说有多重要
I know how important that is to you.
但是告诉我
But tell me,
诚实地说
and tell me honestly...
我们现在这种状态
this, what we have...
对你来说就足够了吗
Is this enough for you?
是的
Yes.
足够了
It is.
但是对我来说不是
Well, it isn't for me.
两位  我需要你们都到表层来
Hey, guys? I need you both in the cortex.
-干什么  -我知道迪沃想做什么了
- Why? - I know what DeVoe's doing.
不是一台机器
It's not one machine.
是许多台  许多台一起运行的机器
They're machines. Machines that work together,
但是它们现在仍旧是分开的
but they're still separate.
卫星
Satellites.
分散的卫星为了一个目的同时运行
Separate satellites working together for a single purpose?
这个人真是个007反派
So this guy really is a Bond villain.
迪沃需要巨大的
DeVoe would need a massive amount
计算能力来确保它们可以
of computational power for them to be able
彼此沟通
to talk to each other.
需要一个能够在各卫星之间
Something to triangulate navigation
进行三角定位的设备
between each satellite.
就像是一台量子计算机
So, like, a quantum computer?
水星实验室刚刚上线了一整套
Mercury Labs just put a whole system
量子计算机系统  就在他们的总部
of quantum computers online, at their home base.
这就是他要去的地方
That's where he's going.
太棒了  这次我们要出其不意地抓到迪沃
Okay, great. This time, we catch DeVoe by surprise.
看看这个
Behold.
沟通我们"大悟之道" 信息的钥匙
The key to communicating our message of the Enlightenment.
多项式时间计算
Polynomial time computing.
梦想将要变成现实
And a dream shall soon become... reality.
克利福德
Clifford!
不许动
Don't move.
巴里  把他打晕  然后铐住他
Barry! Knock him out, and then cuff him!
马上
On it!
吉普赛  现在
Gypsy, now!
快停下  你要把他杀死了
Stop it, you're killing him!
西斯科  小心
Cisco, look out!
巴里  再来一次
Barry, hit him again!
够了
Enough!
凯特琳
Caitlin.
凯特琳  你到底在干什么
Caitlin, what the hell are you doing?
让她回来
Bringing her back.
迪沃正在制造一个声波脉冲
DeVoe is creating a sonic pulse.
你们得离开那里...
You need to get out of there before--
我明白  你想让我吓到你
Oh, I get it. You'd like me to frighten you
从而让你变成你的另一半
into becoming your better half.
乐意至极
Gladly.
迪沃
DeVoe!
大人讲话  小孩子别插嘴
Children should be seen, not heard.
我确信看到你的挚友死亡
I'm very sure seeing your bestie die
足够吓到你了
would be frightening enough,
但是我不能杀死闪电侠
but I can't kill the Flash.
不是在现在
Well, not just yet.
我的"大悟之道"计划
My plan for the Enlightenment
以后还用得到他
requires his further participation.
而你  就没那么走运了
You, however... are a lot less fortunate.
巴里  他要杀了吉普赛
Barry, he's gonna kill Gypsy!
现在你感觉怎样
Now, do you feel that?
脖子周围
Around your throat?
这是在用和我箱子一样重量的压力
That is the gravitational equivalent
捏爆你的喉咙
of my boot busting your windpipe.
她是无辜的  放开她
She's innocent. Leave her alone!
克利福德
Clifford...
这不是我们计划的一部分
This isn't part of our plan.
西斯科  快醒过来
Cisco, wake up! Wake up!
我们的计划是拯救他们
Our plan is to save them.
你不可能拯救所有人  亲爱的
Well, you can't save everyone, my love.
迪沃
DeVoe!
也许
Perhaps.
但我不能就这样看你再杀害一个无辜的人
But I won't watch you kill an innocent life again.
你会的
Yes, you will.
求你了  克利福德
Please. Clifford.
记起你的本性
Remember who you are.
这真是你现在愿意赐予的真理吗
Is this truly the lesson you wish to bestow today?
把箱子拿来
Get the case.
辛西娅
Cynthia!
发生了什么  快醒醒  没事的
What happened? Come on, it's okay.
他对她做了什么
What did he do to her?
和我说话  快醒醒
Hey, talk to me. Come on, it's okay.
你没事的  没事的
You're okay. You're okay.
结果  5个单元
过去12小时中没有失窃报告
No thefts have been reported in the last 12 hours.
那迪沃已经拿到他所有需要的了
So DeVoe managed to get everything he needed.
而我们仍不知道他下一步要做什么
And we still don't know what his next step is.
他说了一些关于大悟之道的事
You know, he said something about the Enlightenment.
那是什么意思
The hell's that supposed to mean?
我知道他在想什么
I know what he's thinking.
我知道他在谋划什么
I know what he's planning.
我们知道他在谋划什么
We know what he's planning.
-哈里  等下  -什么
- Harry, wait. - What?
我可以给他们克利福德的备忘录版本
I can give them the Cliff's Notes version.
不不
No, no.
被偷走的零件部分是为了创造出每颗卫星
The component parts stolen to create each satellite
那将会拥有30腕尺量级的系统
will possess a 30... cubit quantum system, okay,
而每个系统...可以...
and each system... is c-capable of--
每个系统能够让高浓度的暗物质
Each system is capable of redirecting
在1亿百万瓦特爆炸的威力下改变方向
concentrated dark matter back to Earth
回到地球
in 10-million-megawatt bursts.
这种量级
Which-- level of which
的毒性足够影响
is toxic enough to affect
地球上每个人的大脑
each and every human brain on the planet
重新启动他们...
and reboot them back to a--
重新启动他们
Reboot them.
回到简易的初始状态
Back to a simplified state.
就像我这样
Just like mine.
迪沃想要移除地球上
DeVoe wants to remove the intelligence
所有人的智慧
of everyone on Earth?
没错
Yes.
没错  巴里  就是这样
Exactly, Barry. Exactly right.
地球19  回收者机构总部
打开缺口
回收机构  中城
我真的准备这么做了
I'm really gonna do this.
你对待我...
You treat me...
就像我是多重宇宙中唯一的女人一样
like I am the only woman in the multiverse,
而我想要更多
and I want more.
我是怎么了
What is wrong with me?
我不知道我怎么了
I don't know what's wrong with me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没什么错的
Nothing's wrong.
一点都没错
Nothing at all.
我想可能有时候
I guess maybe sometimes,
1加1就是等于2  你知道吗
one plus one just equals two, you know?
你要怎么办
What are you gonna do?
等等
Wait.
拜拜  辛西娅
Good-bye, Cynthia.
拜拜  西斯科
Bye, Cisco.
惊喜
Surprise!
这是什么
What is this?
这是你的宝宝派对  宝宝
It's your baby shower, baby!
所以你整天脑子里都在唱着
This is why you were singing
依帕内玛女孩
"The Girl From Ipanema" in your head all day.
他准备了好些天了
He has been planning this for days.
太甜了
Oh, this is so sweet!
在这种时候把大家都喊来
I feel really guilty pulling everybody away
我挺内疚  但...
at a time like this, but--
庆祝的完美时刻
It's the perfect time to celebrate.
身边都是家人
Surrounded by family.
你们大家
You guys!
宝宝一定能感到满满的爱
This baby is gonna be so loved.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
去和他谈谈吧
Why don't you go talk to him?
你还好吗
Hey, man. Are you okay?
不太好
Not really, no.
想要静静吗  还是...
Do you want some space, or...
实际上我现在已经安静得不行了
Actually, I got plenty of that right now.
抱歉逼你俩
I'm sorry for pushing the two of you.
但我觉得你俩做的是对的
I think you both did the right thing, though.
那为什么这么痛苦
Then why does it hurt so much?
凯特琳
Caitlin.
我觉得你不该再这么做
Look, I don't think you should do that again.
你会害死自己的
You could have gotten yourself killed.
-我得让她回来  -我们会的
- I have to get her back. - We will.
不  我自己能做到
No. I will.
克利福德
Clifford.
没事的
Ow! It's fine.
It's fine.
线路中断的时候  我就来了
When the line cut out, I came.
马上就来了
Immediately.
我以为要失去你了
I thought I'd lost you.
你不会的  克利福德
You'll never lose me, Clifford.
你是对的
You were right.
科技变成了毒瘤
Technology has become a cancer.
驱动文明消耗自身
Driving civilization to consume itself.
一个民兵组织发现了我创造的
A militia group found out about the water purifier
水净化器
that I created.
他们就杀了好多人为了得到它
And they just killed dozens of-of people to take it.
女人和孩子被屠杀
Women and children slaughtered.
就为了一点科技
For a simple piece of technology.
你的日记
Your journal.
描绘了一个世界  在那里人们忘记了
wrote of a world where humanity forgot
科技进步会带来怎样的祸害
that this technological menace was capable.
但我没告诉你的...
But what I didn't tell you...
就是我当时在其中看到了真理
...was that I saw the truth in it even then.
那吓坏了我
And it frightened me.
所以我跑了
And that's why I ran.
现在我再也不怕了
And I'm not frightened anymore.
你相信了
You believe.
我相信你
I believe in you.
让大悟之道启蒙他们  克利福德
Enlighten them, Clifford.
你是唯一能做到的人
You're the only one who can.
没有你我什么都不是
I'm nothing without you.
这椅子可以修复你骨折的地方
The chair will rejuvenate your fractured scaphoid.
准备卫星集合
Prepare the satellites for assembly.
-我说了  准备  -不
- I said, prepare the-- - No!
最初  我们是要开启大悟之道
Initially, we set out to enlighten the world.
现在你想统领它
Now you want to rule it.
我要离开你了  克利福德
I am leaving you, Clifford.
没有什么能进出
Nothing can get in or out.
你竟敢在人类伟大觉醒的前夕
You dare orchestrate an exodus
精心安排自己的离开
on the eve of humanity's greatest reckoning?
你宣誓了
You made a vow.
对我丈夫的宣誓
To my husband!
但我的丈夫已经死了
But my husband is dead.
是思考者的第一个受害者
The Thinker's first victim.
大悟之道也会降临到你头上的  马尔利泽
The Enlightenment will come for you too, Marlize.
我会是唯一的幸存者
I will be all that remains.
克利福德
Oh, Clifford.
没了我你什么也不是
You are nothing without me.
特别快递
Special delivery!
肚子已经好大啦
Wow! You're super pregnant!
今晚之后大概还有21天就生啦
Looks like you're due about 21 days from tonight, I'd say.
我是说  要我猜的话
I-I mean, if I were guessing.
宝贝  是谁
Sweetheart, who is it?
有人给我们送了尿布包
Uh, someone sent us a diaper bag.
看上去那是一个想让你俩
It looks like it's a gift from someone
知道你们有多特别的人送的礼物
who wanted you both to know how special you are.
这个人明白时间珍贵
Someone who understands that time is precious
而且是我们现在仅剩下的一切
and right now is all we've got.
相对而言
Relatively speaking.
-爸爸  -看看我们收到了什么
- Dad? - Hey, look what we got.
谁送的  沃利吗
Who sent that? Wally?
沃利已经送了摇篮车
Wally already sent us a bassinet,
就和摩西[先知]用的一样
which apparently was owned by Moses.
有便条吗
Was there a note?
是谁
Who was it?
一个送快递的女孩
Some delivery girl.